

SARAH PAO

Multidisciplinary UX Designer

sarahpja@gmail.com Syracuse, NY 13224

Summary

UX designer with a background in mechanical engineering. Multidisciplinary creator passionate about developing engaging experiences in the digital and physical space. Specialize in minimizing frustration by solving user problems with the help of data.

Skills

- User research and usability testing
- Information architecture
- Technical communication
- Prototyping, wireframing, user flow
- Visual design in Figma, Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator
- Basic understanding of HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Experience

Customer Service Associate

07/2021 - 01/2023

Lowe's Home Improvement | Syracuse, NY

- Addressed inquiries, resolved customer issues, and managed customer relations.
- Prioritized the safety of coworkers and shoppers by communicating with managers regarding repeated safety nonconformances
- Trained new hires on products and services, best practices and procedures to reduce operational shrink.
- Recommended and initiated product offerings to meet customer changing needs.

Associate Mechanical Engineer

07/2017 - 09/2019

Carrier Corporation | Syracuse, NY Sustaining Engineer

- Analyzed sales data to understand customer needs and teamed up with field engineers to address customer questions and complaints
- Supported manufacturing team with production problems
- Investigated high-failure products for root causes and worked with both internal and external groups toward a solution

New product development

 Conducted simulation to evaluate system performance and capacity to meet 2023 requirements

Research Assistant 02/2013 - 05/2017

Rochester Institute of Technology, RIT | Rochester, NY

- Researched in mechanical properties of polylactic acid (PLA) blends for packaging applications
- Designed experiments and developed processes for producing and testing samples on multiple pieces of equipment
- Organized, analyzed, and presented data to aid the decision-making process

- Trained new assistants on various test equipment
- Produced extrusion-blown films and 3D printing filaments from custom formula PLA blends for multiple research groups

Projects

Non-profit Organization Webpage Redesign

Alley Cat Allies

Redesign the layout and reorganize content on the Take Action landing page to show relevant information at the top of the page. Add a clear CTA to the page. Update the site for a more minimalist style to decrease the user's cognitive load. Redesign the navigation menu with meaningful labels.

Government Agency Homepage Redesign

US Department of Education

Update the department of education's website homepage for a more modern look and eliminate multiple side navigation menus by introducing hierarchy to the main navigation and content.

Mobile App Design

JED

Create a mobile app to solve common problems online shoppers and small business owners face. Identify user problems, brainstorm solutions, and create prototypes for testing. JED is a platform that focuses on building trust between the seller and customers. Customers have access to detailed information on the product and a cost breakdown of each item they purchased. Information about the sellers is easy to find and customers can also support them with donations.

Education and Training

Certificate: UX/UI 11/2022

06/2017

University of Minnesota - Twin Cities | Minneapolis, MN

Bachelor of Science: Mechanical Engineering Technology

Rochester Institute of Technology | Rochester, NY

- 3.94 GPA
- Graduated summa cum laude
- Outstanding Undergraduate Scholar Award Recipient

Portfolios and Profiles

- https://sarahpja.github.io/PortfolioSite/index.html
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/sarahlpao/